Savann Thorn, PMP

Contact

Richmond, VA 23226 (804) 316 – 1301 savann.thorn@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/savannthorn

Key Skills

Business Development
Contracts and Procurement
Consulting
Data Analytics
Financial Analysis & Reporting
Machine Learning
Data Modeling
Negotiation

Public Speaking Python

Operations

R Programming

R&D Sales

Supply Chain Management SQL

Certifications

Project Management Professional PMI, PMP# 2937169

Education

MSBA(C), Business Analytics, The College of William and Mary

BSBA, Accounting and Finance
Old Dominion University

AS, Mathematics and Statistics
J. Sargeant Reynolds CC

Profile

Executive with over 13 years of experience with a strong passion for policy, creating positive impact for all stakeholders while maintaining profitability, and sustainability through strategic direction guided by analytical research. Strong operational skillset and sound project management methodology. Ability to complete projects on time and in budget. Proven leader effectively communicating with all stakeholders. Specialized experience is qualified in the cover letter.

Experience

April 2007—Present

40+ HRS/WEEK

Managing Director • Khem Precision Machining • Richmond, Virginia

- -13+ years business development, financial management, operations
- -41% hit/win on bids of contracts under \$150,000 (SAT)
- -60% hit/win on bids of contracts over \$150,000 (SAT)
- -Utilize database mgmt to filter, identify opportunity autonomous
- -Database management skills, Excel, SQL, Python, R Programming
- -Strong sales cycle successful within 90 days; 2% cold call hit
- -Full Cycle of new business within 18 months from ideation to cash
- -Built and enforced management systems ISO 9001:2015
- -Awarded contracts w/ NAVSEA, NAVSUP, DHS, DLA, ARMY, NAVO
- -Design, additive/subtractive/joining, finishing, material science
- -Managed 10MM+ of spend internationally: materials, subcontractor
- -Prepared and controlled regulatory oversight (DCMA, NSEO, ITAR)
- -Full P&L responsibility, GAAP, DCAA indirect cost pools, tax books
- -Managed investment revenue stream resulting in 30%+ CAGR
- -Strong project manager with MS Project, Gannt, work process tables
- -Strong public speaking at conferences. Command Presence.
- -Built ISO 17025 capable metrology laboratory: Zeiss CMM
- -Strong management of 3rd party professional services: Legal, Tax
- -Strong supplier controls with audit and enforcement experience
- -Developed, capitalized R&D relationships with research universities

September 2001—April 2007

40+ HRS/WEEK

Section Leader • United States Army • Ft. Benning, Georgia

Airborne Infantryman serving in two combat tours, commending on battlefield leadership. Coached and mentored on safety.

September 1996—January 2001

40+ HRS/WEEK

Network Analyst • Circuit City Stores • Richmond, Virginia

Significant exposure in areas of VSAT and terrestrial network infrastructure, service delivery, security & disaster recovery, data & voice network operation/ control over 600+ campus locations. AS/400, VMware, CCNA, IEEE TCP/IP.



Savann Thorn

HAS BEEN FORMALLY EVALUATED FOR DEMONSTRATED EXPERIENCE, KNOWLEDGE AND PERFORMANCE IN ACHIEVING AN ORGANIZATIONAL OBJECTIVE THROUGH DEFINING AND OVERSEEING PROJECTS AND RESOURCES AND IS HEREBY BESTOWED THE GLOBAL CREDENTIAL

Project Management Professional (PMP)®

IN TESTIMONY WHEREOF, WE HAVE SUBSCRIBED OUR SIGNATURES UNDER THE SEAL OF THE INSTITUTE

Tony Appleby

Chair, Board of Directors

Sunil Prashara

President and Chief Executive Officer

PMP® Number: 2937169

10 January 2021

09 January 2024



